Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, founder
of Family First Financial Services, MBA Finance and have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years and today I
am presenting to you the term
plan of IIC Prudential Life Insurance. IIC Pru still has I Protect Smart in pure term plan.
They also have a term plan of I Protect Smart Return of Premium.
Keeping the customer in mind, they have also launched a ULIP plan along with the term plan,
called Protect and Gain. They have recently launched a product called
I Wish, keeping women in mind, where they have surgery or maternity benefit.
Keeping women in mind, they have also launched this type of product
which comes under the health category and today they have launched a new product
Pure Term Insurance I Protect Super on 13 December 20224 and
have kept in mind those people who are the backbone of India, that is, self-employed people whose income
is low or less education, whose income is between 3 lakhs to 5 lakhs. There are many
people in India who are not getting term plans. So keeping those people in mind, ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance has launched a new pure term plan today.
I am going to give you details in this video.
Watch the full video. If you like the video, please subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS.
On youtube.be channel, you will
also get detailed information about other plans of ICICI Prudential Life Insurance. You can also see that playlist and you can get information about
all the term plans, saving plans and pension plans present there. So
go to that playlist and if you want to watch separate videos of ICICI Prudential, you
can watch that too. The population of India, which is currently around
140 crore, out of which only 20 crore people are earning persons who are earning income.
There are two categories in them, one is salaried people and the other is self-employed people. There
are 6 crore people in the salary, out of which 4 crore people have an income of 5 lakhs or more. And 2
crore salaried people are earning income between 3 lakhs and 5 lakhs
but among the self-employed, there are 8 crore people whose income
is between three to 5 lakhs and they are not getting a pure term plan.
So keeping them in mind, ICICI Potential has launched this product
which even self-employed people with low salary can purchase and people with high salary can also
purchase but the focus of the company is that people who are
not able to take term insurance, whose income is low or because of low education, they are
not able to take it. So keeping them in mind, this product has been launched. For example,
look at this picture carefully, here there are four different people, all four have different
professions, all four have different ages, all four have different incomes and all these people
do not file income tax return (ITR), due to which they are not able to take a term policy,
whether it is of ICICI or any other company. But here, even if you
are not filing ITR, you will still get this plan. Let us understand how. Let us talk about
the eligibility criteria of this plan. This plan can be purchased by a person between 18 and 55 years of age. It
is necessary to be 12th pass in education.
Your minimum income should be ₹ 1 lakh and the minimum insurance amount here will be 50 lakhs and
the maximum you can take insurance up to 1 crore. Riders for accidental cover and
disabilities are also available in it. You can make
premium payment on limited pay as well as regular pay. In limited pay, you
will get options of F pay, 7 pay, 10 pay, 15 pay and pay till A60. The biggest feature of this plan is that
there is no requirement of income proof in it. In such cases, where
your income database is already digitally available to the company, ICICI Potential
has a database of about 85% of them available which is used for digital transactions.
Or their income is digital, like if you do online shopping, you spend digitally, the
shopping you do with credit card or debit card, there
are credit bureaus, nowadays even if you go to watch a movie, you swipe the card, if you purchase fashion jewellery,
then as per this digital database the company
will give you this term plan even without income proof, if those whose digital database is not available, then the company
can ask them for their ITR or salary slip as income proof, but the
digital database of most of the customers is available with the company, till now
all the term plans sold by ICICI Prudential, be it I Protect Smart or I Pro
Out of the 92% digital database is available with the company,
out of which 85% have a digital income of Rs. 3 lakh or more,
which means you will see that the database of most of the customers is available digitally with the companies,
many people must be thinking that they have lied about their income
or have not shown it, many times it happens, then the
company manages all the databases somewhere or the other, so if you have a digital database, then you
can easily purchase this policy even under no income proof and if
your number or your name or your information is not present in the digital database, then you
will have to provide income proof. In the new plan I Protect Super, medical test of every customer
will be mandatory. Now who are the people who will not be
able to purchase this plan? What are the exclusions? Those who come under negative pin code,
those who come under high risk in DRC calculator, those who are NRIs, students, housewives or
people involved in agriculture, they cannot purchase this policy and non-individuals,
that is, You cannot purchase this policy under group insurance.
Only individuals can purchase this policy. There
is an excellent feature in this policy called premium break. You have to intimate the company 30 days in advance
that if I am not able to pay the premium this year, then the company will not let your policy lapse that year.
Your policy will continue and even if it terminates during that period, the company will give you a claim.
You will be able to exercise this option only after 5 years and once exercised
, it is necessary to have a gap of 5 years again . You cannot take this option in
the last year of the policy. You can take it as many times during the entire policy term
but there should be a minimum gap of 5 years in between. The year you
do not pay this premium, the next year you will have to pay the premium to the company by adding the premium of that year and the premium of the previous year which you did not
pay. Another excellent
feature has been given in this called smart exit, which many people also call zero
cost insurance policies. This is inbuilt, you do not need to pay
any additional premium for it. But to avail this option, your
minimum policy term should be 25 years or more and
you can exercise this option only after you are 60 years of age or more. That means if you
have reached the age of 60, 61 or 65 and now you feel that you need to
withdraw all the money you have deposited, then you can withdraw the entire amount under smart exit,
otherwise the policy will be closed but the option to withdraw the money deposited
is given here, which is known as smart exit, zero cost.
Three options are given, you can take natural cover, normal cover, you can take
insurance cover up to one crore, in the second option you can take accidental disabilities and
normal cover, in the third option you can take normal cover, accidental disabilities and
accidental death, if you want to take all three together, you can also take it. There
is also a discount in this plan, if you are in the top 35 cities, you will get a discount of 8%.
That too for lifetime. If you are a female, you will get a discount of 15%, not
only for the first year, but every year. And if you already have any kind of
policy in ICICI Provincial, you will get a loyalty discount of 7%, but that
will be only for the first year. So if a female has purchased the policy, if you are in 35 cities and there
are also assisting customers, then they will get a huge discount here. Let's assume that
a person of 35 years of age is taking a pure insurance cover of 50 lakhs till the age of 75
and he is in non-35 cities, then his premium comes to
15219, but if he comes in the top 35 cities, then the premium will be ₹1, but if she
is a female, then she will get another discount of 15%, so she will get the policy for 901 and
if she is also a female assisting customer, then she will get the policy for 068. There will be a discount of about 27%,
out of which 22% will be for lifetime. Let's talk
about the policy. Surrender benefit in this policy Benefits and features If you
opt for limited pay, then you will get surrender benefit. Surrender benefit
option is not available in regular pay. Talking about policy loan,
you will not get any type of loan in this policy. You will get tax benefit in income tax section ATC.
That benefit is always tax free. Talking about grace pay and free loan,
then these will be available to you for 30 days. So now let us understand
the new term plan of ICICI Dence Life Insurance, I Protect Super,
along with benefit illustration, the company has very smartly mentioned all the features here.
It has been explained which you
will understand easily. Secondly, in the benefits, they have also told that
even if you do not pay the premium for 12 months, your insurance cover starts and the policy does not lapse.
Here they have highlighted the option of breaking the premium. Let us assume that a 35-
year-old person named Anil Rajpat is purchasing a policy and
taking an insurance cover of Rs 50 lakh and up to Rs 60 lakh, that is, he is taking a policy term of 25 years
and here his premium is coming out to be Rs 1045. With GST,
the premium will be Rs 854. If we look at ICICI Prudential,
till now they have covered nearly 10 crore policies and 10 crore individuals.
The Asses Under Management is Rs 3.08 lakh crore, which means the company
is a big company worth more than Rs 3 lakh crore. They have also provided a lot of
benefits in bonus and individual policies. Tax benefits are available here.
Information about quick claim settlement is also given. Let us see here. In this way,
the name of the product that will come in your policy bond is ICICI Pru I Protect Super Care. This
is a non-participating non-linked life individual pure risk insurance plan
and here you are paying a regular premium of Rs. 1045 for 45 years. Here
you can see the premium etc. Here you will also get a customer information sheet
, I will tell you about it in detail later.
Let us take another example where the same
person is taking the same 25-year term, but this time he is
also taking an accidental cover of Rs. 50 lakhs and a disability cover of Rs. 50 lakhs. So now if there is a natural death, then
you will get Rs. 50 lakhs. If there is death in an accident, then you will get one year. If there is no death in an accident
but there is a disability, then you will get Rs. 50 lakhs and the insurance cover will still start and
the premium here will be Rs. 18108. ICICI's product team.
The calculation of the applicable taxes is wrong here. Check it a little. 5733
GST here. If it is not possible then please rectify it a little because 10000
is 3000 or 13 and two 15 15 and 5 should be 20000 but it is only 18000.
GST cannot be levied on 15000 and 5000. So there is a little calculation mistake here,
please check that a little. ICICI concern person, now here the complete details have been mentioned,
you have to pay a premium of 18108. Let's take another example where
the customer's income is only 35 and this time he is purchasing an insurance cover of one crore rupees, he is
also taking a disability cover of one crore and accidental cover of one crore, so
it is coming to 2698. Here also the calculation of tax is a little bit wrong, but here
if you go down then here you will see eight figures that
how much amount after GST, etc., the amount, final amount remains the same but
the calculation of GST is a little different. It is different, everything else is mentioned correctly here.
If you want to take an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore, then it
will be available for Rs 998 pure, GST surcharge will be available for Rs 18,000. If you want to take a rider for accidental death,
then it will be available for Rs 000 with GST, disability will be available for Rs 80
with GST. You will get Rs 1 crore for Rs 4600. With GST, the basic premium will be Rs 2698, and
your premium
will be Rs 505. Let us take another example, where I have
tried to tell in limited pay that the customer will pay the premium for 10 years, the policy
will run for 25 years, in that case the premium is coming for Rs 2591. Now here you will see that
the guaranteed surrender benefit is visible, whereas in the other examples,
you were not able to see the surrender benefit because surrender benefit is not available in regular pay, it
is available in limited pay, here only for 10 years.
The policy is running for 25 years. If you want,
you can get coverage for 25, 30, 35, 40 years or even till the age of 85. I am giving you one final example where
if a female purchases the policy, she gets a discount. So, this
policy of Rs.50 lakh is available for Rs.940 for 25 years. And here you will notice
that in the first year it will come for Rs.9000, then it will come for Rs.1075. Here,
the discount of around Rs.15 per cent for females will remain for lifetime.
And if there is an assisting customer, then she
will get the discount and if you are in the top 35 cities, then you will get their discount as well. So, here
you will be able to purchase the policy for a premium of Rs.1075. Females
get the policy at a discount. After the changes that came on October 1, 204, when the policy goes to the customer, every insurance company
will give the policy summary in the first few pages itself. An information sheet will have to be given where
Customers should first look at a few pages to find out what exactly are the benefits and features of their policy.
For example, initially, they will see that
they have purchased the product by supervising ICICI,
here their policy number will be visible. What kind
of product is this, whether it is a saving plan, term insurance, health plan, information
will be available about whether their premium is coming, whether they have insurance cover, for how many years,
and whether they will pay the premium, what will be their policy term, what will be the match benefit in the policy,
what will be the death benefit, all these information will be available to them on the initial page.
If they go to surrender, what surrender benefits will they get, what will be the lock-in period, whether riders
are there or not, what is grace paid, what is free look paid,
what are the rules of the lapse policy, as paid is not available in this plan,
the details of revival will be available, you will be told about the loan, the procedure of claim, i.e.
whether it is TET or not, the small requirements, in how much time
will they be fulfilled, its link will be found here, as if you click on this link So
you will know that if there
is any requirement in proposal or communication or e-policy, then it will be solved in a day. If
you have any requirement in policy copy etc., then it
will be solved in 15 days. Policy service will be solved in a day. Premium due
intimation will be given to you one month in advance. Refund of proposal deposit will be given
to you within a few days. Free look refund will be given to you within a day if you get free look done, money will be received by you within a day
if you surrender, money will be received within a day if there is maturity or survival
benefit or AT, then it will be paid to you on the date on which your death is happening.
Death claim will be received by you within 15 days if it is a case of investigation
then you will get it within 45 days. If there are all the different rules and
regulations of the health policy, then you will get all this information through this link. In the same way,
if you need any assistant for all other information like for example, for claim, then you
can call this toll free number. You can call on this number or you can call on this number if there
is a health related death claim then you can email here you
can download the claim form etc. from here or by going to the link you will click on report claim
you can report by entering the policy number or mobile number or email id or PAN number and
date of birth you can also report about your claim it
will be done online also apart from this whatever information you will need
physical claim form link is also mentioned here if you want to take physical information
then you will get a lot of information here plus one more thing is mentioned here
like if you are claim settlement made gg for you
you can also claim online by going to dd i website as I told you can also do SMS
here you have to write ICICI claim here you have to space you
have to write your policy number 56767 you can also send SMS then your
claim will be registered you can email claim support
i.com you can go to the nearest aaa prlf insurance branch or call
on toll free number
You can also call on 18266 for claim. So here you
will get all this information at the beginning of the policy. If you have to make any complaint etc.,
then you can complain on this number. You can call on this number. If you
have to complain to IRD, then the email ID for complaining to IRD has also been mentioned.
You can also complain to IRD through these two email IDs. So
you will get a lot of information in this customer information sheet
. If I talk about this plan, then it is a boon for self-employed or low-salary income people.
If they want to take a big insurance cover, a lot of good features have also been given here,
riders have also been given. Option of smart exit has also been given.
So if you want to purchase this plan from me, then you can call me on 0940 3412.
If you want to know whether this type of plan
is cheaper than ICICI plan or other company has a better plan, then you can consult me.
To compare and buy you
will get more videos from me on whatsapp2 which
will help you in financial planning like term plan, saving plan, retirement, child education, marriage etc. Thank you so much, Jai
Hind